## RITESH KUMAR GUPTA

### Data Scientist | Data Analyst | Machine Learning

**Highly analytical and process-oriented data analyst** with in-depth knowledge of database types; research methodologies; and big data capture, curation, manipulation and visualization. Furnish insights, analytics and business intelligence used to advance opportunity identification, process reengineering and corporate growth.



### **Personal Info**

#### **Address**

SHAPUR NAGAR HYDERABAD, TELANGANA, 500055

#### **Phone**

970 559 8107

#### E-mail

riteshgupta7355@gmail.co

#### LinkedIn

https://www.linkedin.com/in/ritesh-kumar-gupta-41b



Python	Excellent
Machine Learning	Very Good
Data Analysis	•••• Excellent
Data Visualization	Excellent
SQL	

Very Good



### **Work History**

2018-10 - Customer Support Executive

2019-10 Q CONNECT BUSINESS SOLUTION LIMITED,

HYDERABAD, Telangana

 Provided excellent customer service by efficiently resolving issues and responding to client inquiries



### **Education**

2014-08 - B.Tech: Computer Science

2018-06 Jawaharlal Nehru Technological University -

Data Science With Al from Social Prachar

Deep Learning with Tensorflow from IBM

HYDERABAD



2019-07

2019-10

### Certifications

Data science with Artion social Fractian
Applied Science with Python from IBM
Machine Learning from IBM



#### 1.Real-Time Face Recognition

Tools: OpenCV, Python

Algorithms: Convolution Neural Network and other

facial detection algorithms

Deep
Learnning

NLP

Very Good

R

Very Good

HTML & CSS

Excellent

Very Good

Very Good

Excellent

# **Tools**

**JavaScript** 

Scikit-learn Very Good Matplotlib Excellent **NLTK** Very Good Jupyter Very Good OpenCV Very Good Tableau Very Good



ggplot2

Excel

English

Superior

Hindi

Native

#### 2.Twitter Sentiment Analysis

Tools: NLTK, Python

**Algorithms:** Sentiment Analysis

3. <u>Youtube Video Recommendation System</u>

Tools: Python, sklearn

Algorithms: Deep Neural Networks, classification

algorithms

4. Spam Classification

Tools: Python, Matplotlib

Algorithm: NLTK

5. Web Traffic Time Series Forecasting

Tools: GCP

**Algorithms:** Recurrent Neural Networks (RNN), Long short-term memory (LSTM), ARIMA-based techniques



### **Achievements**

Completed Data Science with Artificial Intelligence course from Social Prachar.

Completed Applied Data science with python, Machine Learning, Data Analysis, Data Visualization and Deep Learning with Tensorflow from IBM.

Earned many Certificates and Badges from IBM.



### **LINKS**

Kaggle Link:- https://www.kaggle.com/ritesh7355



#### **Interests**

Artificial Intelligence

Coding / Programming